Guide to the Frank Altschul Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Writings by Frank Altschul and Others, 1910-1974
  - Letters To Editors and Related Correspondence, 1910-1974
    - New York Times, 1962 October 29 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - AFL-CIO Free Trade Union News, 1964 August (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - New York Times (unsent), 1965 November 5 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - New York Times, 1971 March 31 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - New York Times, 1971 June 20 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - New York Times, 1973 January 8 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - New York Times, 1973 August 31 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - New York Times, 1974 July 8 (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Articles About Frank Altschul
    - New York World-Telegram, 1933 September 26 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - General, 1938-1961 (Box 69, Folder 23)
  - Editorials and Related Correspondence, 1945-1948
    - Subjects A-L (4 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Subjects M-Ru (3 Folders) (Box 71, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Subjects S-Z (2 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Selected Editorials, 1945-1948 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Chronological Index, 1945-1948 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Subject Index, 1945-1946 (2 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Subject Index, 1947 (2 Folders) (Box 73, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence on Editorials, 1947 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and Letters to Stamford Advocate from Readers, 1945-1947 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews and Related Correspondence
    - Reviews, 1947-1951 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Book Reviews for Saturday Review and Related Correspondence, 1951-1969
      - Peace Can Be Won, by Paul Hoffman, 1951 April 21 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - The Defense of Europe, by Drew Middleton, 1952 May 31 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Isolation and Alliances, by Walter Lippmann, 1952 October 10 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - The Challenge to American Foreign Policy, by John J. McCloy, 1953 July 11 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Common Sense and World Affairs, by Dorothy Fosdick, 1955 January 29 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - The Public Philosophy, by Walter Lippmann, 1955 February 19 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - The Oppenheimer Case, by Charles R. Curtis, 1955 October 15 (Box 73, Folder 12)
      - Choice for Survival, by Louis Halle, 1958 March (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Ideas, People and Peace, by Chester Bowles, 1958 April 12 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - Foreign Policy: The Next Phase, by Thomas K. Finletter, 1958 May 24 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - The Great Arms Race, by Hanson Balwin, 1958 July 26 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Foreign Policy and the Free Society, by Walter Millis and John C. Murray, 1958 August 30 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Strategic Surrender, by Paul Kecskemeti, 1958 September 6 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - On War, by Raymond Aron, 1959 January 19 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - What's Wrong with U.S. Foreign Policy, by C.L. Sulzberger, 1959 March 14 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Five Ideas That Change the World, by Barbara Ward, 1959 March 21 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Common Sense and Nuclear Warfare, by Bertrand Russell and The Devil's Repertoire, by Victor Golancz, 1959 April 18 (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Germany and the East-West Crisis… by Eilliam S. Schlam, 1959 May 30 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - America, The Vincible, by Emmet Hughes, 1959 August (Box 74, Folder 12)
      - Strength of Men and Nations, by William Ernest Hocking, 1959 October 32 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - Political Realism and the Crisis of World Politics, by Kenneth W. Thompson, 1960 April 2 (Box 74, Folder 14)
      - Live and Let Live, by Stuart Chase, 1960 May 28 (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - Can We End the Cold War? by Leo Perla, 1960 July 30 (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - Between War and Peace, by Herbert Feis, 1960 October 1 (Box 74, Folder 17)
      - The Necessity for Choice, by Henry Kissinger, 1960 January 14 (Box 74, Folder 18)
      - A Forward Strategy for America, by Robert Strausz-Hupe, 1961 February 25 (Box 74, Folder 19)
      - Japan Subdued, by Herbert Feis, 24 June 1961. (Box 74, Folder 20)
      - The United Nations and US Foreign Policy, by Lincoln P. Bloomfield, 1961 July 1 (Box 74, Folder 21)
      - The Balance of Terror, by Pierre Gallois, 1961 November 25 (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - Has Man A Future? by Bertrand Russell, 1961 December (Box 74, Folder 23)
      - Appeasement: A Study in Political Decline, 1933-39, by A.L. Rowse, 1962 January 13 (Box 74, Folder 24)
      - Appeasement: Road to War, by William Henry Chamberlain, 1962 March 3 (Box 74, Folder 25)
      - The Limits of Defense, by Arthur I. Waskow, 1962 March 24 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - The Hard Way to Peace, by Amitai Etzioni, 1962 April 28 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - An Approach to Peace and Other Essays, by H. Stuart Hughes, 1962 May 26 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - On the Prevention of War, by John Strachey and Hostage America, by Robert A. Dentler and Phillips Cutright, 1963 March 16 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Unarmed Victory, by Bertrand Russell, 1963 September 7 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Prospects for the West, by J. William Fulbright, 1964 January 4 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Suicide of the West: An Essay on the Meaning and Destiny of Liberalism, by James Burnham, 1964 April 25 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - The Futile Crusade: Anti-Communism as American Credo, by Sidney Lens, 1964 July 4 (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - The President as World Leader, by Sidney Warren, 1964 October 10 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Détente: Cold War Strategies in Transition, by Eleanor Lansing Dulles, and Robert Dickson Crane, 1965 April 17 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - The Cold War… and After, by Charles O. Lerche, Jr. and After Twenty Years: Alternatives to the Cold War in Europe, by Richard J. Barnet and Marcus Raskin, 1965 August 14 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Beginnings of the Cold War, by Martin Herz, 1966 March (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - The Arrogance of Power, by J. William Fulbright, 1967 February 11 (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - The Diplomacy of a New Age, by Dexter Perkins, 1967 June 10 (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Crisis Now, by James Gavin, 1968 March 2 (Box 75, Folder 15)
      - The Limits of Power, by Eugene McCarthy, 1967 October 21 (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - A Peace Policy for Europe, by Willy Brandt, 1969 March 2 (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Essays, Articles, and Notes with Related Correspondence, 1924-1971
    - International Exchange--Notes and Memoranda, 1924-1943 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - International Exchange, 1924-1943 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - NY Stock Exchange--Notes and Memoranda, 1925-1939 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Republican Party--Notes and Memoranda, 1932, 1938 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - "Revolution by Inadvertence"--Essay, 1937 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - "The Challenge to Republican leadership"--Essay and Correspondence, 1938 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - WWII--Notes, Memoranda, and Proposals for Post-War Stabilization, circa 1940 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - "Let No Wave Engulf Us," 1941, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - "Chance of Our Lifetime," 1942 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - List of Articles and Reviews, 1942 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - "The Nature of the Problem," circa 1953 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - "America's New Economic Role" in Foreign Affairs Magazine--Correspondence and Notes, 1953 April (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Memorandum, 1953 August (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Committee for the Present Danger and "Do We Deserve to Survive?" 1953-1954 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Unpublished Article on John Foster Dulles--Notes, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Joseph McCarthy--Notes and Articles, 1954 February (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - "Reflections on Suez"--Clippings and Correspondence, 1956, 1962-1964 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - "Reflections on Disarmament in the Light of the Arden House Conference," 1961 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - "Cuba: A Turning Point in World History?"--Notes for Unpublished Article, 1962 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Essay on Impressions of Israel, 1963 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Republican Party and Foreign Policy--Memorandum, 1964 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - "Reflections Upon Returning from State Department Meeting on International Cooperation Year," 1965 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - General Memoranda, circa 1971 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Printed Materials, 1932-1953 (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Writings by Others
    - General, 1933-1961 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Buell, Raymond, 1942-1944 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Goodhart, Arthur L., undated (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Goodhart, Arthur, 1955-1970 (4 Folders) (Box 78, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1957-1961 (Box 78, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Subject and Political Files, 1919-1986
  This series is comprised of two subseries, Subject Files and Political Files
  - Subseries IV.1: Subject Files, 1919-1986
    This eclectic subseries contains files on a wide range of subjects that were of interest to Altschul, ranging from chess and stamps to disarmament and Judaism. Some files contain clippings and general information on a subject, while others relate more directly to Altschul's personal activity; under "books," for example, there is information about Altschul's private collection, including correspondence regarding book purchases, collection lists, and invitations to book club events and author luncheons. The series also contains Altschul's address books and biographical information collected for his entry in Who's Who in Commerce and Industry. Files are arranged alphabetically.
    - Address Book, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 78, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Addresses, 1949-1951, 1967-1968 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Altschul, Frank and Helen--Affiliations and Biographical Information, 1957-1986 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - American International Exhibition in Moscow, 1959 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Art Correspondence, A-Z, 1927-1950 (6 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 4 to 9)
    - Books Correspondence
      - D-G, 1919-1932 (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Maggs Brothers, 1919-1932 (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Me-Pr, 1919-1932, (3 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Pyson Printers, 1919-1932 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Q-V, 1919-1932, (2 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 5 to 6)
      - A-Q, 1933-1951 (4 Folders) (Box 81, Folder 1 to 4)
      - R-Z, 1933-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 82, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Books
      - Book and Author Luncheons, 1939-1940 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - The Colophon, 1929-1934 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - "Recollections of the Gillis Press," by Walter Gillis--Manuscript, 1919 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Library of Frank Altschul--General, 1933-1940 (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Library of Frank Altschul--Valuation, 1934-1946 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - General, undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - O'Hara, John Myers--"Mythologic Scenes" by Henri De Regnier, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Perez de Oliva--Manuscript on Christopher Columbus--Correspondence and Related Materials, 1929-1954 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Sloog, M.--Correspondence, 1933-1945 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Sloog, M.--List of Books, 1934 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Chess, 1937-1966 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Disarmament--Correspondence, 1959-1973 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Disarmament--Printed Materials, 1959-1973 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Fuller, General John Frederick Charles, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Germany
      - Clippings, 1920-1921 (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - General Notes and Quotations, circa 1940 (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Memo to Dean Rusk, 1962 May 17 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and Clippings, 1964-1972 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - "Reflections on the Max Kohnstamm Dinner," 1966 December 7 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Great Britain--Clippings and Printed Materials, 1952-1965 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Greece, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Israel
      - Correspondence and Memoranda, circa 1964 (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Printed Materials, 1963-1971 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Jews and Judaism
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1933-1945 (2 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Correspondence A-F, 1933-1945 (2 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Correspondence G-Z, 1933-1945(3 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Anti-Semitic Literature--General, 1933-1942 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Anti-Semitic Literature--Sidney Hillman Campaign, 1944 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1955-1979 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Manuilski, Dmitri, 1955-1956 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Mayflower Case, 1948 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Poems and Poetry, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Stabilization, 1943-1945 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Stamps, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - USSR, 1974 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Subseries IV.2: Political, 1932-1978
    This subseries documents Altschul's political activity. Correspondence files contain his letters to U.S. senators, representatives, and other political figures, as well as their responses. Campaign files consist primarily of correspondence between Altschul and other supporters and discuss the progress of his favored candidates and the distribution of pamphlets and articles on their behalf. Both correspondence and campaign files are arranged alphabetically by politician name. The subseries also holds smaller groups of files relating to Altschul's campaign contributions, his participation in several Republican campaign drives, and subject files on voting issues, particularly black voter turnout in the 1930s and 1940s.
    - General Correspondence A-Z, 1937-1951, (5 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 1 to 2)
    - General Correspondence A-G, 1955-1976 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence H-Z, 1955-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Bailey, Josiah W., 1937-1939 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Baldwin, Raymond E., 1942-1946 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Barton, Bruce, 1937-1941 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Bell, Mrs. George H., 1941-1950 (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Bradley, J. Kenneth, 1942-1960 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Bricker, John W., 1939-1944 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Bridges, H. Styles, 1937-1950 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Brooks, C. Waylon, 1937-1940 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - Castle, William R., 1938-1939 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Chadbourne, William, 1938 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Church, Frank, 1959-1970 (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Darmstadter, Doris, 1938-1939 (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - Davenport, Russel W., 1940 (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Dewey, Thomas E., 1937-1944 (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Douglas, James H., 1938-1940 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Dulles, John Foster, 1953-1959 (4 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1952-1940 (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Frank, Glenn, 1938-1940 (3 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 6 to 8)
      - Gillespie, Kingsley, 1942-1948 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Goodspeed, C.B., 1937 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Hallahan, Walter S., 1939-1944 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - Hallek, Charles A., 1937-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Hamilton, John, 1936-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Hannegan, Robert E., 1944-1947 (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - Hard, William, 1937-1938 (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Hewitt, William M., 1938-1939 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Hilles, Charles D., 1936-1945 (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Hillman, Sidney, 1944 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - Hogan, Harry G., 1940-1944 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Hollister, John B., 1938-1943 (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Hoover, Herbert, undated-1939 (Box 93, Folder 6)
      - Howe, William S., 1939-1944 (Box 93, Folder 7)
      - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Kennedy, John F., 1960-1963 (Box 93, Folder 10)
      - Landon, Alf M., 1936-1944 (Box 93, Folder 11)
      - Lindsay, John V. 1963-1973 (Box 93, Folder 12)
      - Lindsay, John, 1972 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Martin, Joseph, 1939-1942 (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - McCarthy, Eugune, 1960-1968 (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - McCarthy, Joseph, 1952-1968 (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - McCullough, Edward R., 1942-1947 (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - McGovern, George, 1967-1973 (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - McMahon, Brien, 1944-1954 (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - Martin, Joseph W., 1939-1942 (Box 94, Folder 8)
      - Morton, Sterling, 1938-1939 (2 Folders) (Box 94, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Murray, William S. 1937-1938 (Box 94, Folder 11)
      - Popkin, Louis, 1939-1940 (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - Pryor, Samuel Jr., 1937-1943 (Box 94, Folder 13)
      - Ransohoff, Babette S., 1943-1948 (Box 94, Folder 14)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1959-1968 (Box 95, Folder 1)
      - Roosevelt, F.D., 1931-1945 (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - Scheftel, Stuart, 1942 (Box 95, Folder 3)
      - Simpson, Kenneth, 1940-1941 (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Sharp, Martha, 1946 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Smith, H. Alexander, 1938-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Taft, Robert A., 1939-1940 (Box 95, Folder 8)
      - Truman, Harry S., 1947-1950 (Box 95, Folder 9)
      - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr., 1939-1948 (Box 95, Folder 10)
      - Waltman, Franklyn, 1938-1940 (Box 95, Folder 11)
      - White, Dudley, 1937-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Willkie, Wendell L., 1939-1968 (4 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Campaigns
      - Herbert H. Lehman, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - General, 1933-1934 (Box 96, Folder 6)
      - Herbert H. Lehman, 1934 (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - General, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1936 (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Alf Landon,1936 (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Fundraising, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - Luncheons, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - Memoranda, 1936 (Box 97, Folder 7)
      - General, 1936 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - Press, Foreign and Jewish, 1936 (2 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Wendell Willkie, 1940,1944 (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - 1944 Campaign (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - Clippings, 1944 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Contributions
      - General, 1944-1951 (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - 1972-1975 (4 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 7 to 10)
      - Requests for Contributions, 1975-1979 (Box 98, Folder 11)
      - General, 1976-1977 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Republican Party
      - Memoranda, undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Memoranda, 1936-1940 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Republican National Committee, 1938-1978 (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Republican Platform, 1936 (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Republican Postwar Policy Association, 1943 (Box 99, Folder 7)
      - Republican Program Committee, 1938 (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Republican Program Committee--"Report to the Committee on the Needs of the Negro," by Ralph Bunche, 1939 (Box 99, Folder 10)
      - United Republican Campaign Fund, 1938 (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - United Republican Finance Committee, 1940 (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - United Republican Finance Committee Drive, 1939 (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - United Republican Finance Drive, 1937 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Stamford Political Files, 1942 (2 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Voting
      - 1944 Election (Box 100, Folder 7)
      - The Negro Vote, 1939-1940 (Box 100, Folder 8)
- Series V: Printed Materials, 1909-1984
  This series contains a collection of article reprints, fliers, brochures, and ephemera relating to Altschul's many interests, particularly social and political issues such as patriotism, Communism, human rights, and education. Some represent the views of individuals, while others were printed by organizations such as the Friends of Democracy and the Foreign Policy Association. Documents are filed alphabetically by author or organization name and occasionally by subject. This series also holds one box of sampled clippings from Altschul's clipping file, representing the type of material he collected from major newspapers.
  - Aberg, Einer, 1954-1969 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Action Committee on American-Arab Relations, undated (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Altschul, Frank--Clippings, 1940-1949 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Altschul, Helen Goodhart--Clippings and Memorabilia, 1909-1964 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - American Association for the United Nations, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - America First, Inc., 1941 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1960-1963 (3 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 1 to 3)
  - American Foreign Policy, 1941-1951 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - American Friends of Anti-Bolshevik Bloc of Nations (A.B.N.), 1952 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - American Jewish Committee, undated (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - American Jewish Committee, Pursuit of Equality, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - American Management Association, 1968 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - American Mercury, 1957-1959 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - American Nazi Party, 1984 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - American Zionist Council, 1957,1960 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - America's Choice, undated (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - Aquatone, undated (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1960-1961 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Bricker Amendment, 1953-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Britten, Frank L., undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Brzezinkski, Zbigniew, 1968-1972 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Carrier Corporation, 1952 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Center for the Study of Diplomatic Institution, undated (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Christian Educational Association, 1967,1969 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Christian Nationalist Crusade, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Cinema Education Guild, undated (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1933-1975 (2 Folders) (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Committee for the Return of Confiscated German and Japanese Property, 1955-1956 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Educational League, 1945 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Council for Christian Social Action (5 Folders), undated (Box 103, Folder 3 to 7)
  - Council for Financial Aid for Education, undated (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Council on World Tensions, 1965 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Democratic Party--Nationalities Division, 1955 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Party--Releases, 1952 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Dilling, Elizabeth, 1943-1947 (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1946-1951 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - East European News Briefs, 1958 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1947 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Ephermera, undated (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Fleisch, Fritz, undated (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Fleming, D.F., 1958 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Governments, 1952-1961 (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1949 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Freedom House, 1962-1964 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Freedom School, 1962-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Friends of Democracy, 1944-1945 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Gerard, E.F.G., undated (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - German Pamphlets, 1952 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Goodhart, A.L., 1967-1972 (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Gospel Tract Society, 1959-1970 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Herald of Freedom, undated (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Hungarian-American Press, 1957-1962 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Holdridge, Herbert C., 1961-1962 (2 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Human Events, 1957 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Immigration Consultation, 1961 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Indonesia, 1958 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Israel: Releases, 1959-1969 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Jefferson School, undated (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Defense League, 1969 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - John Birch Society, 1963-1965 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1963 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1947 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Klu Klux Klan--Texas, 1965 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Labor Unions--Releases, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - League for Peace with Justice in Palestine, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--Clippings, 1963 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - McCarran Immigration Act, 1953 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Masryk, T.G., 1962 (Box 106, Folder 3)